Rabo Yusuf

raboyusuf94@gmail.com || LinkedIn Profile || Github Profile || Portfolio

SUMMARY:

Frontend Software Engineer with 3 years of experience working with different kinds of web technologies. Skilled in solving problems with Google Cloud, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript, React, React Native, Redux, SQL, MySQL and NodeJs. Focused on being a valuable part of any team I am on and believe in the team rising together. If one portion of the team needs help with a task, I have no issue jumping in to assist with anything required.

CERTIFICATION:

- AlgoExpert Data Structures and Algorithms
- Nano Degree in React, Redux, and React Native

SOFT SKILLS:

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Time Management
- Collaboration

EXPERIENCE:

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

The Bulb Africa, Lagos Nigeria

April 2021- Present

- Refactored old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Collaborated with management, internal, and development partners regarding software application design status and project progress.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Colab Tech, Kaduna Nigeria

Jan 2019 – March 2021

- Developed software for desktop and mobile operating systems.
- Refactored codebase from ECMAScript 5 to ES 6, improving user engagement by 10%.

EDUCATION:

Masters in Engineering (Mech. Eng., CGPA 4.38) April 2015 – Aug 2018 Bayero University Kano. Kano State, Nigeria